Jason Woodson

jwoodson2014@gmail.com | (804)-921-2290 | https://jwoodson2014.github.io/home/

SUMMARY

Dedicated worker and innovative thinker with 3 years of professional experience in consulting and a strong background working with big data and performing data analysis. Currently pursuing a Master's in Business Analytics at the University of Iowa and looking for a position in data science or data analytics.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Master of Science, Business Analytics, University of Iowa

December 2022

Bachelor of Science, Accounting and Information Systems, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

May 2018

Bachelor of Science, Finance, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

May 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, R. Python, SAS, Basic VBA Programming

Visualization: Tableau

Data Analysis: Advanced Microsoft Excel, Alteryx, JMP, Orange, Databricks

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Iowa – Iowa City, Iowa

Boe Research Fellow

 $May\ 2022-August\ 2022$

- Collected, scraped, and cleaned six seasons worth of data on Formula 1 racing
- Performed exploratory analysis and used machine learning to build a model that recommends successful tire strategies for drivers based on factors such as tire choice, race laps, weather, etc.
- Final model achieved an accuracy and precision of 71% and 68%, respectively
- https://tippie.uiowa.edu/news/2022/08/bringing-moneyball-f1-racing
- Skills: R, Advanced Microsoft Excel, Orange

KPMG LLP – Washington, D.C.

Securitization Tax Senior Associate

October 2020 – August 2021

- Advised clients on strategies for the taxable consequences of collateralized loan obligations and other fixed income securities, including risk retention strategies related to the Dodd-Frank Act and the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act
- Assisted in the development of KPMG's first internal, cloud-based processing system used to automate processes around analyzing cash flows of fixed income securities to advise clients more accurately on tax planning matters over the life of collateralized loan obligations
- Led the implementation of functions within the system to automate manual processes such as PDF text extraction and autogenerating summary templates that increased productivity by upwards of 35%
- Oversaw the work of five first and second year associates while assuring the timely completion of deliverables for over 50 deals within a 3-month period
- Responsible for maintaining project budgets to meet strict profit margin goals set by directors and partners
- Skills: Python, VBA Programming, Advanced Microsoft Excel, Alteryx

Securitization Tax Associate

October 2018 – October 2020

- Analyzed complex cash flows and transactions, sometimes in excess of 10,000, for the tax planning and reporting for collateralized loan obligation (CLO) issuers, including clients with AUM in excess of \$10 billion
- Clients include five of the top twenty CLO managers in the United States
- Skills: VBA Programming, Advanced Microsoft Excel

LEADERSHIP

Mentor, Higher Achievement

September 2019 – May 2021

- Volunteered as a mentor for 5th and 6th graders in Washington, D.C. public schools
- Conducted sessions once a week centered around current events to help students learn about topics directly affecting students

Elected Member, Chesapeake Advisory Staff Counsel, KMPG LLP

August 2019 - August 2021

- Served as head of the "Lunch and Learn" Committee and planned informational events for staff across the Chesapeake region
- Organized information session for first-time home buyers and resources on how to better your mental health in the workplace